Guide to the Frank Foster Papers, 1930-2013 and undated, bulk 1950s-2009 RL.00408
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Compositions by Others Series, 1930-2004 and undated, 24 boxes
  - Letter-Sized Materials, 6 boxes
    - Naima. Coltrane, John, undated (Box 42)
    - Nefertiti. Shorter, Wayne, 1968 (Box 42)
    - The Onliest. Hurst, Robert (Byrd, Donald), 1987 (Box 42)
    - Perdido. Tizol, Juan. Lyrics by Erwin M. Drake, and Hans van Lengsfelder, undated, 2 folders (Box 42)
    - Ruby My Dear. Monk, Thelonious, 1992 and undated (Box 42)
    - Scandia Skies. Dorham, Kenny, undated (Box 42)
    - The Shadow Of Your Smile. Mandel, Jonny. Lyrics by Paul Francis Webster, undated (Box 42)
    - Shorty George. Basie, William Count, and Andy Gibson, undated (Box 42)
    - Sleigh Ride. Anderson, Leroy. Lyrics by Mitchell Parish, undated (Box 43)
    - Smoke Gets In Your Eyes. Kern, Jerome. Lyrics by Otto Harbach, undated, 2 folders (Box 43)
    - Soon. Gershwin, George. Lyrics by Ira Gershwin, undated, 2 folders (Box 43)
    - Sophisticated Lady. Ellington, Edward Kennedy Duke. Lyrics by Irving Mills, and Mitchell Parish, undated, 2 folders (Box 43)
    - Soul Eyes. Wadron, Malcolm E., undated (Box 43)
    - Stablemates. Golson, Benny,1954 (Box 43)
    - Stardust. Carmichael, Hoagy. Lyrics by Mitchell Parish, 1928, 1929, 1930 (Box 43)
    - Stars Fell On Alabama. Perkins, Frank E. Lyrics by Mitchell Parish, undated (Box 43)
    - Step Into My Dream. Taylor, Billy, undated (Box 43)
    - Steppin' Wit' Ganz. McKinney, Carlos, undated (Box 43)
    - Straighten Up And Fly Right. Cole, Nat King, and Irving Mills. Lyrics by Nat King Cole, and Irving Mills, 1944, 1973 (Box 43)
    - Street Of Dreams. Lewis, Sam, and Victor Young (Box 43)
    - Swingle Jingle Bells. Traditional Christmas Carol, undated (Box 43)
    - Take The "A" Train. Strayhorn, Billy, 1941 (Box 43)
    - There'll Be A Time. Jones, David L., 2006 (Box 43)
    - This Can't Be Love. Rodgers, Richard. Lyrics by Lorenz Hart, undated (Box 43)
    - A Time For Love. Mandel, Johnny. Lyrics by Paul Francis Webster, undated (Box 43)
    - Tin Tin Deo. Gillespie, John Birks Dizzy, undated (Box 43)
    - Tis Autumn. Nemo, Henry, undated (Box 44)
    - To You. Jones, Thad. 1961, 1981 (Box 44)
    - Tones For Joan's Bones. Corea, Chick, undated (Box 44)
    - Weekend. Dameron, Tadd. Lyrics by Irving Reid, undated (Box 44)
    - What A Woderful World. George, Douglas, Robert Thiele, and George D. Weiss. Lyrics by Douglas George, Robert Thiele, and George D. Weiss, 1967 (Box 44)
    - What Are You Doing New Year's Eve? Loesser, Frank, undated (Box 44)
    - What's New? Haggart, Robert. Lyrics by Johnny Burke, 1939, undated, 2 folders (Box 44)
    - When Your Lover Has Gone. Swan, E. A., undated (Box 44)
    - Where Or When. Rodgers, Richard. Lyrics by Lorenz Hart, undated (Box 44)
    - Young And Foolish. Hague, Albert. Lyrics by Arnold B. Horwitt, undated, 2 folders (Box 44)
    - You're A Joy. Dameron, Tadd, 2004, undated, 2 folders (Box 44)
    - You've Changed. Fischer, Carl. Lyrics by Bill Carey, undated, 4 folders (Box 44)
    - Zec. Jones, Thad, undated (Box 44)
  - Legal-Sized Materials, 7 boxes
    - After You've Gone. Layton, Turner. Lyrics by Henry Creamer, undated (Box 48)
    - All Is Fair In Love. Wonder, Stevie, undated, 2 folders (Box 48)
    - Atlantic City. Undated (Box 48)
    - Blue On Blue. Undated (Box 48)
    - Blues Medley. Undated (Box 48)
    - Broadway. Undated (Box 48)
    - Brushes And Brass. Undated (Box 48)
    - Caravan. Tizol, Juan, Undated (Box 48)
    - A Child Is Born. Jones, Thad. Lyrics by Alec (Lafayette Chew) Wilder, undated (Box 48)
    - Close To You. Bachrach, Burt, and Hal David, undated, 2 folders (Box 49)
    - Dat Dere. Brown, Oscar, undated (Box 49)
    - Dear John. Hubbard, Freddie, undated (Box 49)
    - Ellington Medley. Ellington, Edward Kennedy Duke, et al., undated (Box 49)
    - The End Of A Love Affair. Redding, Edward, undated (Box 49)
    - Falling In Love Is Wonderful. Berlin, Irving, arranged by Bob Ojeda, undated (Box 49)
    - Far From Over. Undated (Box 49)
    - Fas' Livin' Blues. Hendricks, Jon, undated (Box 49)
    - The Finer Things In Life. Hendricks, Jon, undated (Box 49)
    - For My Lady. Thielemans, Jean Toots, undated, 2 folders (Box 49)
    - Giant Steps. Coltrane, John, undated (Box 50)
    - Groovin' High. Gillespie, John Birks Dizzy, undated, 2 folders (Box 50)
    - Half As Much. Peak, Curley Williams, undated (Box 50)
    - Hava Nagila. Traditional, undated (Box 50)
    - Here's That Rainy Day. Van Heusen, Jimmy. Lyrics by Johnny Burke, undated (Box 50)
    - Hey Good Lookin'. Williams, Hank, undated (Box 50)
    - How Deep Is The Ocean. Berlin, Irving, undated, 2 folders (Box 50)
    - How Insensitive. Jobim, Antônio Carlos. Lyrics by Moraes de Vinicius, undated (Box 50)
    - I Don't Care. Marrs, Stella, undated (Box 50)
    - I Wish You Love. Chauliac, Léo. Lyrics by Charles Trenet and Albert A. Beach, undated (Box 50)
    - If I Should Lose You. Rainger, Ralph. Lyrics by Leo Robin, undated (Box 50)
    - In A Mello[w] Tone. Ellington, Edward Kennedy Duke. Lyrics by Gabler Milt, undated (Box 50)
    - Invitation. Kaper, Bronislau, undated (Box 50)
    - It Don't Mean A Thing. Ellington, Edward Kenney Duke. Lyrics by Irving Mills, undated, 2 folders (Box 51)
    - It Only Happens Every Time. Composed and Arranged by Thad Jones, 1969, 1973 (Box 51)
    - I'll Never Be The Same. Malneck, Matt and Frank Signorelli. Lyrics by Gus Kahn, undated, 2 folders (Box 51)
    - I've Grown Accustomed To Her Face. Loewe, Frederick. Lyrics by Alan Lay Lerner, undated (Box 51)
    - Jean Marie. Matthews, Ronnie, undated, 2 folders (Box 51)
    - Joy Spring. Brown, Clifford, undated, 2 folders (Box 51)
    - Ko-Ko. Parker, Charlie, 1999 (Box 52)
    - Long Ago (and Far Away). Kern, Jerome D. Lyrics by Ira Gershwin, undated (Box 52)
    - Love For Sale. Porter, Cole, undated (Box 52)
    - Moanin' The Blues. Williams, Hank, undated (Box 52)
    - "My Fair Lady" Medley. Loewe, Frederick. Lyrics by Alan Lay Lerner, undated, 2 folders (Box 52)
    - Newborn. Mixon, Danny, undated (Box 52)
    - [On] Green Dolphin Street. Kaper, Bronislau. Lyrics by Ned Washington, undated (Box 52)
    - Out Of Nowhere. Green, Johnny. Lyrics by Edward Heyman, undated (Box 52)
    - Pensive Miss. Composed and Arranged by Neal Hefti, undated (Box 52)
    - Samba Do Brilho. Vergueiro, Guilherme, undated (Box 53)
    - Secret Love. Undated (Box 53)
    - Shorty George. Basie, William Count, and Andy Gibson, undated (Box 53)
    - Scandia Skies. Dorham, Kenny, undated (Box 53)
    - Sentimental Journey. Brown, Les, and Ben Homer. Lyrics by Bud Green, undated (Box 53)
    - Somethin' 'Bout Believin'. Ellington, Edward Kennedy Duke, undated (Box 53)
    - Sophisticated Lady. Ellington, Edward Kennedy Duke. Lyrics by Irving Mills, and Mitchell Paris, undated, 2 folders (Box 53)
    - Stars Fell On Alabama. Perkins, Frank E. Lyrics by Mitchell Parish, undated (Box 53)
    - Stops-And-Goes. Hendricks, Jon, undated (Box 53)
    - Street Of Dreams. Warren, Harry. Lyrics by Al Dubin, undated (Box 53)
    - Summer Frost. Undated (Box 53)
    - Thanks Absolutely. Hendricks, Jon, undated (Box 54)
    - Trying To Drink The Blues Away. Undated (Box 54)
    - Walkin' My Baby Back Home. Ahlert, Fred E. Lyrics by Roy Turk, undated (Box 54)
    - Waltz Medley No. 1, "Falling In Love With Love" and "I'll Take Romance". Rodgers, Richard et al., undated (Box 54)
    - What Would You Do. Undated (Box 54)
    - Young And Foolish. Hague, Albert. Lyrics by Arnold B. Horwitt, undated (Box 54)
    - You've Changed. Fischer, Carl. Lyrics by Bill Carey, undated (Box 54)
  - Oversized Materials, 1930-2009, 10 boxes
    - After You've Gone. Layton, Turner. Lyrics by Henry Creamer, undated, 2 copies (Box 25)
    - All Is Fair In Love. Wonder, Stevie, undated (Box 25)
    - All The Things You Are. Kern, Jerome. Lyrics by Oscar Hammerstein II, undated (Box 25)
    - Alright O.K. You Win. Watts, Mayme, and Sid Wyche, 1992 (Box 25)
    - Angel Eyes. Dennis, Matt. Lyrics by Earl K. Brent, undated, 3 copies (Box 25)
    - Basie 2004 Excerpt No. 1, "Basie". Basie, William Count, 2004, 2 copies (Box 25)
    - Basie 2004 Excerpt No. 2, "Corner Pocket". Green, Freddie, 2004 (Box 25)
    - Basie 2004 Excerpt No. 4, "Lil' Darlin'". Hefti, Neal, 2004 (Box 25)
    - Basie In Mind. Scott, Shirley, undated (Box 25)
    - Beyond The Sea. Trenet, Charles. Lyrics by George Benson, and Jack Lawrence, undated (Box 25)
    - Blues Medley, "Sweet Little Angel" and "It's My Own Fault". 1991 (Box 25)
    - Bright Moments. Kirk, Rahsaan Roland, undated (Box 25)
    - A Child Is Born. Jones, Thad. Lyrics by Alec (Lafayette Chew) Wilder, 1979 (Box 25)
    - Close To You. Bachrach, Burt, and Hal David, 1987 (Box 25)
    - Counterblocking. Composed and Arranged by Thad Jones, undated (Box 25)
    - Dear John. Williams, Hank, 1993 (Box 25)
    - Ellington Overture. Strayhorn, Billy, et al., 1977 (Box 25)
    - Ellington Medley, "Satin Doll", "Sophisticated Lady" and "Take The 'A' Train". Ellington, Edward Kennedy Duke, et al., 1983 (Box 55)
    - The End of a Love Affair. Redding, Edward, 1992, 4 copies (Box 55)
    - A Fine Romance. Kern, Jerome D. Lyrics by Dorothy Fields, 1988 (Box 55)
    - Firm Roots. Walton, Cedar, 1988, 3 copies (Box 55)
    - Five For Max. Undated (Box 55)
    - Fly by Night. Tull, Jethro, and Ian Anderson, 1969 (Box 55)
    - For My Lady. Thielemans, Jean Toots, 1992, 2 folders (Box 55)
    - Giant Steps. Coltrane, John, 1991, undated, 2 folders (Box 56)
    - Hava Nagila. Traditional, 1988 (Box 56)
    - Have You Met Miss Jones. Rodgers, Richard. Lyrics by Lorenz Hart, 1991 (Box 56)
    - Here's That Rainy Day. Van Heusen, Jimmy. Lyrics by Johnny Burke,1992, 3 copies (Box 56)
    - Hey Good Lookin'. Williams, Hank, 1993 (Box 56)
    - Hills Of The North Rejoice (The Great and Terrible Day of the Lord). Darwall, John. Lyrics by Charles Oakley, undated, 2 copies (Box 26)
    - How Deep Is The Ocean. Berlin, Irving, 1993 (Box 26)
    - How Insensitive. Jobim, Antônio Carlos. Lyrics by Moraes de Vinicius, 1993, 2 folders (Box 26)
    - I Don't Care. Marrs, Stella, undated (Box 26)
    - If I Should Lose You. Rainger, Ralph. Lyrics by Leo Robin, 1990, 2 copies (Box 26)
    - If This Isn't Love (Sarah Vaughan Tribute Opening). Lane, Burton. Lyrics E. Y. Harburg, undated (Box 26)
    - If You Could See Me Now. Dameron, Tad, 1999, 3 copies (Box 26)
    - I'm Gettin' Sentimental Over You. Bassman, George. Lyrics by Ned Washington, 1993 (Box 26)
    - In A Sentimental Mood. Ellington, Edward Kennedy Duke, 1994, undated, 2 folders (Box 26)
    - It Don't Mean A Thing. Ellington, Edward Kenney Duke, and Irving Mills, undated (Box 27)
    - I'll Close My Eyes. Reid, Billy. Lyrics by Buddy Kaye, undated (Box 27)
    - It's Only A Paper Moon. Arlen, Harold, E. Y. Harburg, and Billy Rose, 1991, 2 folders (Box 27)
    - I've Grown Accustomed To Her Face. Loewe, Federick. Lyrics by Alan Jay Lerner, 1993 (Box 27)
    - Joy To The World. Handel, George Frideric, 1992 (Box 27)
    - Just Friends. Klenner, John. Lyrics by Sam M. Lewis, undated (Box 27)
    - Kansas City. Leiber, Jerry. Lyrics by Mike Stoller, 1992, 2 copies (Box 27)
    - Let Me Off Uptown. Evans, Redd, and Earl Bostic, undated, 2 copies (Box 27)
    - Long Ago (and Far Away). Kern, Jerome D. Lyrics by Ira Gershwin, undated, 2 copies (Box 27)
    - Love At Sundown. Bhumibol Adulyadej, His Majesty The King, 1993, undated, 2 folders (Box 27)
    - Love The [Th'] Girl. Byrd, Donald, 1993, undated (Box 27)
    - Lover. Rodgers, Richard. Lyrics by Lorenz Hart, 1994, 4 copies (Box 27)
    - Lover Come Back to Me. Romberg, Sigmund. Lyrics by Oscar Hammerstein, undated, 3 copies (Box 57)
    - Maiden Voyage. Hancock, Herbie, undated (Box 57)
    - Mambo Inn. Bauza, Mario, 1992, 2 copies (Box 57)
    - Moanin' The Blues. Williams, Hank, 1993 (Box 57)
    - Moment's Notice. Coltrane, John, undated (Box 57)
    - More Than You Know. Youmans, Vincent. Lyrics by Billy Rose, and Edward Eliscu, 1983, undated (Box 57)
    - Morning Mist. Composed and Arranged by Roger Hamilton Spotts, undated (Box 57)
    - My Baby Upsets Me. Williams, Joe, undated (Box 57)
    - "My Fair Lady" Medley, "On The Street Where You Live". Loewe, Federick. Lyrics by Alan Jay Lerner, undated (Box 57)
    - My Funny Valentine. Rogers, Richard. Lyrics by Lorenz Hart, 1992, 2 copies (Box 57)
    - Newborn. Mixon, Danny, undated (Box 57)
    - On Green Dolphin Street. Kaper, Bronislau. Lyrics by Ned Washington, 1986, 1989, 2 folders (Box 57)
    - Out Of Nowhere. Green, Johnny. Lyrics by Edward Heyman, 1994 (Box 57)
    - Ruby My Dear. Monk, Thelonious,1992, 2 copies (Box 57)
    - Scandia Skies. Dorham, Kenny, undated, 3 copies (Box 58)
    - Scrapple From The Apple. Parker, Charlie, 1994, 3 copies (Box 58)
    - Sentimental Journey. Brown, Les, and Ben Homer. Lyrics by Bud Green, 1988 (Box 58)
    - Shorty George. Basie, William Count, and Andy Gibson, 1960 (Box 58)
    - Skylark. Carmichael, Hoagland. Lyrics by Johnny Mercer, 1987, undated (Box 58)
    - Sophisticated Lady. Ellington, Edward Kennedy Duke. Lyrics by Irving Mills, and Mitchell Parish, 1985 (Box 59)
    - Stella By Starlight. Young, Victor. Lyrics by Ned Washington, undated (Box 59)
    - Stompin' At The Savoy. Goodman, Benny, Edgar Sampson, and Chick Webb. Lyrics by Andy Razaf, undated (Box 59)
    - Stops-And-Goes. Hendricks, Jon, 1990 (Box 59)
    - Sweet and Lovely. Arnheim, Gus, Charles N. Daniels, and Harry Tobias. Lyrics by Gus Arnheim, Charles N. Daniels, and Harry Tobias, 1990, 3 copies (Box 59)
    - They Say That Falling In Love is Wonderful. Murrell, Chris, 1993, 2 copies (Box 60)
    - There'll Never Be Another You. Arranged by Bob Ojeda, undated (Box 60)
    - 'Tis Autumn. Nemo, Henry, undated (Box 60)
    - The Very Thought Of You. Noble, Ray, 1987, 2 copies (Box 60)
    - Waltz Medley No. 1, "Falling In Love With Love" and "I'll Take Romance". Rodgers, Richard, et al., undated, 2 folders (Box 60)
    - What's New? Haggart, Robert. Lyrics by Johnny Burke, 1993, 2 copies (Box 61)
    - What Would You Do. Hendricks, Jon, undated (Box 61)
    - When Your Lover Has Gone. Swan, Einar Aaron, 1990 (Box 61)
    - Without A Song. Youmans, Vincent. Lyrics by Billy Rose and Edward Eliscu, 1989 (Box 61)
    - Young And Foolish. Hague, Albert. Lyrics by Arnold B. Horwitt, undated (Box 61)
    - You've Changed. Fischer, Carl. Lyrics by Bill Carey, 1990, 5 copies (Box 61)
    - Ypso-Facto. Ridley, Larry, 1989 (Box 61)
  - Miscellaneous Manuscripts, Undated, 1 box
    Miscellaneous scores, parts, and fragments of compositions by Foster, by others, and of unknown authorship.
    - Catfish Sa'mich. Undated. (Box 28)
    - Cherry Point. Undated. (Box 28)
    - Didn' You. Undated. (Box 28)
    - Just The Way You Look Tonight. Kern, Jerome. Lyrics by Dorothy Fields, undated. (Box 28)
    - Miscellaneous Manuscripts, undated., 2 folders (Box 28)
    - Sign-Off. Undated. (Box 28)
- Personal Files Series, 1930-2013 and undated, 10 boxes
  Files kept by Foster on a variety of subjects and content, including business records, musical collaborations, teaching and pedagogy, jazz composition and arranging, copyright information, publicity, family history, news clippings, and information on organizations and individuals. There are also folders of personal correspondence, Foster's writings (including extensive sketches for an autobiography), and photographs of Foster and others. Arranged alphabetically by folder title.
  - Aaron Davis Hall, 2004 (Box 29)
  - ASCAP, 2000, 2004, 2005 (Box 29)
  - Autobiography (17 folders) (Box 29)
  - A Basie Rap-jam, 1993 (Box 30)
  - Artists Collective, Inc. Pays Tribute to Dr. Frank Foster plaque, 2000 April 1 (Box 64)
  - Basie Orchestra, 1964, 1994, 2004 (Box 30)
  - Basie Centennial, undated (Box 30)
  - Benny Golson Jazz Master Award plaque, 1998 March 19 (Box 64)
  - Birthday memorial, 2011 (Box 66)
  - BNY Mellon Jazz 2009 Living Legacy Award plaque, 2009 October 2 (Box 64)
  - College of St. Rose, 1993-1996 (Box 30)
  - Conyers, 1995, 1997 (Box 30)
  - Copyrights, 1961-2003, 1966-2004, 1969, 1971, 1976 (3 folders) (Box 30)
  - Count Basie Society (Red Bank Special), 2004 (Box 30)
  - DSO, 2002, 2003 (Box 30)
  - Family Tree, undated (Box 30)
  - Frank Foster's Big Band Arrangements, undated (Box 30)
  - George Gee, 1994-1996 (Box 31)
  - Georgia White, undated (Box 31)
  - Great and Terrible Day (Sketches), 1991-1997 (2 folders) (Box 31)
  - Harmony and Theory, 1999 (Box 31)
  - Harry Fox Agency, Inc., 2000-2008 (Box 31)
  - IAJE (International Association of Jazz Educators), 1994 (Box 31)
  - In Defense of Be-Bop pamphlet, 1979 (Box 66)
  - International Jazz Hall of Fame plaque, 1996 June 15 (Box 64)
  - Interview with Frank Foster, undated (Box 31)
  - Invoices, 1995, 2000, 2002-2004, 2007 (Box 31)
  - Jazz Artists / Vocalists, 1994-1995 (Box 31)
  - Jazz Journal International, 1983 (Box 31)
  - Jazz Spiritual Suite, undated (Box 31)
  - Jazz Standards, undated (Box 31)
  - Jazzmobile Workshop, undated (Box 31)
  - Jimmy Heath Compositions, undated (Box 31)
  - Jones Series, undated (Box 31)
  - Lead Sheets, 1980, 1981, 1996 and undated (Box 31)
  - Leo Rising, 1980, 1997, on compact disc (Box 31)
  - Letters, 1979-1996 (Box 31)
  - Letters, 1996-2007 (Box 32)
  - Letters, 1987, 1994, 2001, 2009 and undated (Box 32)
  - Lillian Foster's Letter, 1937 (Box 32)
  - Loud Minority Band, 2002, 2007 (Box 32)
  - Lyrics, 1988, 1989, 1991 (Box 32)
  - Marlena Shaw, 1998 (Box 32)
  - Memories, 1974-1978, 1992, 1975-1995, undated (4 folders) (Box 32)
  - Mike Woods letter, undated (Box 32)
  - National Music Publishers' Association, 1996-1998, 2001, 2006 (Box 32)
  - On Vocal Jazz Improvisation, undated (3 folders) (Box 32)
  - Orchestration, 1988, 1999, 2003, undated (3 folders) (Box 33)
  - Original Lyrics to Songs, undated (Box 33)
  - Original Tunes, 1971-2002 (Box 33)
  - Pending Projects, 2002 (Box 33)
  - Photographs (8 folders) (Box 33)
  - Photographs (11 folders) (Box 34)
  - Photographs, 1930s-2013 and undated; 6 folders (Box 65, Oversize-folder 1)
  - Pop-I-N Sheet Music Collection (Box 37)
  - Postage Stamps, undated (Box 37)
  - Programs, 1977, 1982, 1997, 1998, 2001, 2004, 2006, 2008, undated (Box 37)
  - Promotional Materials, 1970s-2011 and undated (Box 66)
    Scope and Contents
    Clippings, bios, event listings, programs, reviews
  - Press Kit, undated (Box 37)
  - Publicity, 1960-2007, undated (6 folders) (Box 37)
  - Rahsaan Roland Kirk, 1974-1976 (Box 37)
  - Rob Duboff letter, 2004 (Box 37)
  - Reviews, 1997-2007 (Box 37)
  - Saxophone Exercise Book, 1994 (Box 37)
  - Saxophone Method, Jazzlines, 1981, 1994, undated (2 folders) (Box 37)
  - Saxophone Method, Jazzlines, 1994, 1995, undated (2 folders) (Box 38)
  - Songwriters, 2007 (Box 38)
  - Song List, undated (Box 38)
  - St. Paul UMC, 2002, 2004, 2005 (Box 38)
  - Stage Diagrams, undated (Box 38)
  - Surviving Success: Changes, Challenges, and Choices by Charlotte V.M. Ottley, 2012 (Box 66)
  - Swing That Music, Inc., 1995, 2002, 2003 (2 folders) (Box 38)
  - Symphonic Jazz Orchestra, undated (Box 38)
  - Thelonious Monk Institute, 1995 (Box 38)
  - Title Covers, undated (3 folders) (Box 38)
  - UNC Jazz Press, 2002-2003 (Box 39)
  - Vanessa Rubin's Letter, 2004 (Box 39)
  - Walnut Hills High School, 1996, 2006, 2007 (Box 39)
  - Walrus Music Publishing, 1988-2004 (2 folders) (Box 39)
  - Warner Bros Publications, 1995, 1999 (Box 39)
  - Writings (prose) by Frank Foster (7 folders) (Box 39)
  - Newspaper articles, 1981-2009 (Box 35)
  - Caricature Drawing, 1987 (Box 35)
- Audio and Moving Image Materials, 1954-2002 and undated, 2 boxes
  Series contains audio and moving image materials in audio cassette, digital audio tape (DAT), CD, VHS, and DVD formats. Series consists chiefly of recordings of Frank Foster's concert performances, including his appearances with both the Count Basie Orchestra and the Loud Minority. Series also contains rehearsal recordings, recording session masters, and a documentary film.
  RESTERICTIONS: All original analog audio and moving image materials are CLOSED to patron use. CD or DVD use copies, which are OPEN to patron use, are available for some items and are noted below. Unless otherwise noted, use copies must be made for access to content.
  - Audio Cassettes
    Original cassette titles retained.
    - Interview - F. Foster, Part 1, KPFK, 2010-0087-001 (Box 62)
    - Interview, Part 2, 2010-0087-002 (Box 62)
    - Interview - F. Foster, 2010-0087-003 (Box 62)
    - Interview - F. Foster, 2010-0087-004 (Box 62)
    - Basie Band In Helsingborg, Sweden, Interviews Green G Foster, 2010-0087-005 (Box 62)
    - In Defense Of Be-Bop, 2010-0087-006 (Box 62)
    - In Defense Of Be-Bop (duplicate), 2010-0087-007 (Box 62)
    - Jazzmobile Workshop, 2010-0087-008 (Box 62)
    - Lake Placid Suite, 2010-0087-009 (Box 62)
    - Lake Placid Suite, 1980, 2010-0087-010 (Box 62)
    - DL Hank and Frank, 1998, 2010-0087-011 (Box 62)
    - Frank Wess, Frank Foster, 1986, 2010-0087-012 (Box 62)
    - Frank Foster - Frank Wess, 2010-0087-013 (Box 62)
    - Manhattan Fever, The Loud Minority, 1970-1979, 2010-0087-014 (Box 62)
    - Elvin Jones, Simone, Shinjitu, 1975, 2010-0087-015 (Box 62)
    - Live At Birdland, 1998, 2010-0087-016 (Box 62)
    - Metropole Orch Hilversum, 1982, 2010-0087-017 (Box 62)
    - K-Luoto, 1997, 2010-0087-018 (Box 62)
    - Birdland All-Stars At Carnegie Hall, 1954, 2010-0087-019 (Box 62)
    - Frank Foster, Metropole Orch., 1982, 2010-0087-020 (Box 62)
    - SUNY at Potsdam, 2010-0087-021 (Box 62)
    - John Addison Concert Hall, 1998, 2010-0087-022 (Box 62)
    - Great And Terrible Day Of The Lord, A Jazzspirational Suite, 1993, 2010-0087-023 (Box 62)
    - Central State, 1982, 2010-0087-024 (Box 62)
    - Copenhagen, Denmark, 2010-0087-025 (Box 62)
    - Lethbridge, 2010-0087-026 (Box 62)
    - Calgary, Alberta, 1987, 2010-0087-027 (Box 62)
    - Fossy Sea Cruise, Oct 19, Set II, 2010-0087-028 (Box 62)
    - Cowings And Shaw, 2010-0087-029 (Box 62)
    - Amy Duncan / Brass Tacks "Monk Creeps In", 1985, 2010-0087-030 (Box 62)
    - "Hymn For Her", "Who's Afraid Of Frank Wolf", 2010-0087-031 (Box 62)
    - Frankly Swinging, 1952-1966, 2010-0087-032 (Box 62)
    - "Hope Meets Foster", "Byrd's Word", 2010-0087-033 (Box 62)
    - Joe Sudler Swing Machine, 2010-0087-034 (Box 62)
    - Carrie Smith, 1979, 2010-0087-035 (Box 62)
    - "Bright Colors", 2010-0087-036 (Box 62)
    - Count Basie, "Easin' It", 2010-0087-037 (Box 62)
    - Count Basie Orchestra, El Morocco, 1992, 2010-0087-038 (Box 62)
    - Count Basie Orchestra, Geo. Benson, Osaka, Japan, 1991, 2010-0087-039 (Box 62)
    - Back To The Apple, Spring Is Here, Basie Orch. 1957-1961, 2010-0087-040 (Box 62)
    - Basie Orch, Carmen Bradford, Diane Schuur, Matsue, 1987, 2010-0087-041 (Box 62)
    - CBO, Hamburg, 1987, 2010-0087-042 (Box 62)
    - George Benson, CBO, 1989, 2010-0087-043 (Box 62)
    - Count Basie Band Led By Frank Foster, El Morocco, Worcester, Mass., Live, 1992, 2010-0087-044 (Box 62)
    - Count Basie Set 1, 1992, 2010-0087-045 (Box 62)
    - Count Basie Orchestra, El Morocco, 1st set, 1992, 2010-0087-046 (Box 62)
    - Cardell's Cornell Count Basie, KDSU FM 92, 1986, 2010-0087-047 (Box 62)
    - Basie's Bag, 1994, 2010-0087-048 (Box 62)
    - Count Basie April In Paris, 1955, 1989, 2010-0087-049 (Box 62)
    - Basie's Bag, 1994, 2010-0087-050 (Box 62)
    - The Count Basie Orchestra Live At El Morocco, 1992, 2010-0087-051 (Box 62)
    - Duke Ellington Orchestra / Count Basie Orchestra, First Time! The Count Meets The Duke, 2010-0087-052 (Box 62)
  - Other Audio Materials